## Rindra Josia Rakotonarivo

## **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

rrindrajosia@gmail.com | Portfolio | Github | Linkedin | Twitter

#### **SUMMARY**

A full-stack developer that can work cross-functionally between the front-end and back-end while managing multiple projects ranging in priority levels.

Proven experience developing customer-focused websites using Ruby on Rails, PHP, CSS, HTML, ES6. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs and Databases.

#### SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: PHP, Ruby, Rails, MySQL.

 $\textbf{Tools \& Methods}{:}\ Git, Git Hub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome$ 

Dev Tools.

**Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

## EXPÉRIENCE

Full-stack developer for 6+ years working on a variety of projects.

# Ministry of Population (Madagascar)

April 2011 - Dec 2019

- Responsible for databases and software
  - Redesigned website that increased the Ministry's reputation and awareness. Link: www.population.gov.mg.
  - Developed GIS web application which helps decision-makers locate the installation of infrastructures (i.e., water supply).

#### Microverse

May 2020 - Dec 2020

Mentor (Volunteer)

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **MICROVERSE**

March 2020 - Dec 2020

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

## AMITY UNIVERSITY (INDIA)

Dec 2010 - Dec 2011

#### Postgraduate Diploma in IT (E-Learning)

- HTML, CSS, PHP, C#, JEE and JavaScript.
- Oracle, MySQL.